six says draw the most stable chair
confirmation of CIS one turb for methyl
cyclohexene we have to have a TB on
carbon 1 we have to have a methyl on
carbon 4 and they have to be CIS to one
another so CIS means they're on the same
side of the ring so we can probably rule
out a couple of these just by noticing
that they're not in the CIS
configuration and so that's going to be
A and B because these are pointing in
different directions A and B are trans
isomers so on a the methyl is up and the
tur be is down on B the methyl is down
and the turb is up so those are actually
trans so that's not going to work now
for C and D these are both examples of
CIS one turb for methyl cyclohexane but
they are not of equal energy these are
the two differing chair confirmations
that are possible and so what do we know